Federal Theatre Project Collection, 1935-1939: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 4: Play Programmes and Notices, 1919 January 10-1939; 2 boxes
  - New York, 1936-1938; portions of 2 boxes
    - “Horse Eats Hat”: Orson Welles and Edwin Denby, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “It Can't Happen Here”: John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “It Can't Happen Here”: John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “The Bad Man”: Porter Emerson Browne, dates not examined; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “The Treasure Hunt”: Andrew Barton, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “Adam and Eve”: Guy Bolton and George Middleton, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - “Be Seated”: Jack Mason, 1936 July 24; 7 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Moving Along”: Frank Merlin, 1936 September; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Moving Along”: Frank Merlin, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Machine Age”: William Sully, 1937 April 30; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Clap Hands”: Harry S. Miller, 1936; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Swing It”: Cecil Mack, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Ask Dad”: Matt Shelvey, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “On Top”: Matt Shelvy, 7/27, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Taking the Air”: R. G. Dare, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “The Dance of Death”: W. H. Auden, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “The Mikado”: Gilbert and Sullivan, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Iolanthe”: Gilbert and Sullivan, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “The Mikado”: Gilbert and Sullivan, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Trial by Jury”: Gilbert and Sullivan, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Pinafore”: Gilbert and Sullivan, 1936; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Tamiris and the Dance Ensemble, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dance Program for Young Folk, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Fantasy 1939”, dates not examined; 3 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Adelante”: Helen Tamiris, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “The Eternal Prodigal”: Gluck Sandor, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Doris Humphrey and Charles Weidman Dance Program, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “Young Tramps”: Don Oscar Becque, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Productions of Federal Dance Theatre, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - “In Heaven and Earth”: Arthur Goodman and Washington Pezet, 1936; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “A Woman of Destiny”: Samuel Jesse Warshawsky, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Backwash”: Edwin Harvey Blum, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Bassa Moona”: Momodu Johnson and Norman Coker, 1937; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Bassa Moona”: Momodu Johnson and Norman Coker, 1937; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Mr. Jiggins of Jigginstown”: Lady Longford, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Seemanns Ballade”: Joachim Ringelnatz, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Einmal Mensch”: Aurel Rasko, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “It Can't Happen Here”: Jon C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Professor Mamlock”: Friedrich Wolf, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “We Live and Laugh”: Judah Bleich and Zvee Scooler, dates not examined; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “The Idle Inn”: Peretz Hirschbein, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - “Mississippi Rainbow”: John Charles Brownell, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Awake and Sing”: Clifford Odets, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The All American Minstrels: Wesley Frazer, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Battle Hymn”: Michael Blankfort and Michael Gold, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Androcles and the Lion”: G. B. Shaw, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Showing Off”: William Sully, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Sing for Your Supper”, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Macbeth”: Shakespeare, 1938; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Macbeth”: Shakespeare, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “It Can't Happen Here”: John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “The Tailor Becomes a Storekeeper”: David Pinski, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Prologue to Glory”: E. P. Conkle, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “A Hero is Born”: Theresa Helburn, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Big Blow”: Theodore Pratt, 1938 October; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Haiti”: William du Bois, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Power”: Arthur Arent, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Pinocchio”: Yasha Frank, 1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “An Enemy of the People”: Ibsen, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Twelfth Night”: Shakespeare, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “On the Rocks”: G. B. Shaw, dates not examined; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Processional”: John Howard Lawson, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Everyman”, 1936 March 31; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “The Conjure Man Dies”, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “In Heaven and Earth”: Arthur Goodman and Washington Pezet, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Tony Pastor's 14th St. Theatre, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Birds”: Aristophanes, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “American Holiday”: Edwin L. and Albert Barker, 1936; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish Plays, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Spirochete”: Arnold Sundgaard, 2/13, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Minstrel Show, 1936 March 31; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “The Showboat”: Julien Berger, 1938 February 16; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Love in Humble Life”: John Howard Payne, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Let us Sing”: Charles Pittenger, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - F. T. P. Notices, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Diff'rent”: Charles Hopkins, 1/25, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Varieties of 1938”, 1938 December 21; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Announcement--Shakespeare Excerpts, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - “The Trial of Doctor Beck”: Hughes Allison, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - “Mississippi Rainbow”: John Charles Brownell, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - North Carolina, 1938 December-1939 May; 1 folder
    - “The Little Crib”: Jacob Borut and Lola Sachs, 1938 December; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Lena Rivers”: Ned Albert, 1938 December; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Saturday's Children”: Maxwell Anderson, 1938 December 9; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “An Old Fashioned Charm”: Juanita Austin, 1938 December 13; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Children of the Moon”: Martin Flavin, 1939 February 7; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Il Travatore”: Verdi, 1939 March 18; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “They Live On”: James Weidon Johnson and Paul Lawrence Dunbar, 1939 April 25; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Rip Van Winkle,”, 1939 May 11; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Penny Wise”: Jean Ferguson Black, 1939 May 16; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Tom Piper and the Pig”, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “The Servant in the House”: Charles Rann Kennedy, 1939 Spring; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “Sherlock Holmes: A Study in Scarlet”: Arthur Conan Doyle, 1939 May 31; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oregon, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - “Counselor at Law”: Elmer Rice, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Spirochete”: Arnold Sundgaard, 2/26, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Timberlane Tintypes”: Yasha Frank, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Hansel and Gretel”: Yasha Frank, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Pinocchio”: Yasha Frank, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “One Third of a Nation”: John C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Alice in Wonderland”: Dean Collins, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - “Prologue to Glory”: E. P. Conkle, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - “One Third of a Nation”: Jonh C. Moffitt and Sinclair Lewis, 10/17, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Puppet Pageant, 4/1, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - “Stepping Stars”, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Washington, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - “Spirochete”: Arnold Sundgaard, 3/8, no year; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Negro Theatre, 1937; 1 folder
    - “Sweet Land”: Conrad Seiler, 1937; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Noah”: Andre Obey, 1937; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Noah”: Andre Obey, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Mississippi Rainbow”: John Charles Brownell, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “One Act Plays of the Sea”: Eugene O'Neill, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Macbeth”: Shakespeare, 7/7, no year; 7 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Macbeth”: Shakespeare, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Macbeth”: Shakespeare, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Turpentine”: J. A. Smith and Peter Morrell, 6/26, no year; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Turpentine”: J. A. Smith and Peter Morrell, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Horse Play”: Dorothy Hailparn, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “The Show Off”: George Kelly, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “The Case of Philip Lawrence”: George MacEntee, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - “Walk Together, Chillun”: Frank Wilson, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Children's Theatre, 1936 July 22-1938; 1 folder
    - “The Revolt of the Beavers”: Oscar Saul and Lou Lantz, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Jack and the Beanstalk”: Charlotte Chorpenning, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Flight”: Oscar Saul and Lou Lantz, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “The Emperor's New Clothes”: Charlotte Chorpenning, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “The Emperor's New Clothes”: Charlotte Chorpenning, 1936 July 22; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “The Emperor's New Clothes”: Charlotte Chorpenning, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Pinocchio,”, 1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Pinocchio”, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “The Ivory Door”: A. A. Milne, 1938 August; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Special Easter Festival of Children's Plays, 1938 April 19; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Special Easter Festival of Children's Plays, 1938 April 19; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Little Black Sambo”: C. B. Chorpenning, 1938 November 16; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Treasure Island”: R. L. Stevenson, 5/27, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - “Mother Goose Goes to Town”, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Children's Autumn Festival, dates not examined; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Marionettes, 1938 July 30-1939 February 14; 1 folder
    - “Stars on Strings”, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Stars on Strings,”, 6/2, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “The Story of Ferdinand”: Monroe Leaf, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “The Birthday Party”, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Snowdrop and the Seven Dwarfs,”, 12/2, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Snowdrop and the Seven Dwarfs,”, 11/30, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Aladdin,”, 1/20, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Marionette Unit,”, 1938 October; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Puppet Pageant,”, May, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Vagabond Puppeteers,”, 1938 October; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Circus Days,”, 1939 February 2; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Circus Days,”, 1938 July 30; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Circus Days,”, 1938 December 22; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Marionette Review”, dates not examined; 7 copies (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Jubilee Singers,”, 1939 February 14; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous programmes, dates not examined; 1 folder
    - “Prologue to Glory”: E. P. Conkle, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - One Act Plays, dates not examined; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - “Chalk Dust”: Harold A. Clarke and Maxwell Nurnberg, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - “Love in Humble Life”: John Howard Payne, dates not examined; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - “The Nativity,”, 12/33, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Yiddish Playbill, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - “Tons of Money”: Evans and Valentine, 12/13, no year; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters enclosed with programmes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Radio division broadcast programmes, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 13 Elizabethan dramas, after 1938 January 1; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Programme sheets, February to November, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series 5: Information Releases, dates not examined; 2 folders
  - Information releases, dates not examined; 5; 3 dated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Education section information releases, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Press releases, dates not examined; 15 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Review of the Play Bureau, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Series 6: Notices and Reviews, dates not examined; 1 folder
  - Short notices in bulletins, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Acknowledgements, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series 7: Newspaper Clippings and Issues, 1935-1938; 5 folders
  - 1935 clippings, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1936 clippings, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1937 clippings, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1938 clippings, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper issues, 1936-1938; 1 folder
    - “America,”, 1936 July 3; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - “Work,”, 1938 April 23; 1938 May 21; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - “Project Councillor,”, 1936; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - “Living Newspaper,”, 1937-1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - “Show Bill,”, 1936 March-April; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series 8: Protest Leaflets and Bills, 1936-1938; 1 folder
  - Leaflets, 1936-1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - “Federal Theater News,”, 1936 February-March; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - “The Prompter,” 3 issues, 1937-1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series 9: Performance Details, 1936-1938; 6 folders
  - Performance schedules, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New York performance schedules, 1936 January-1937 May; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lists of performances, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Lists of New York performers: Names and addresses, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minstrels performances, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Notes and biographies on minstrels, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rough drafts for shows, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Show bills, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Route sheets, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Route sheets and locations for New York marionette performances, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Company time sheets, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Company time sheets for New York performances, 1937-1938; portion of 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Blank company reports, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Series 10: Marionette Unit, dates not examined; 2 folders
  - Bulletin of marionette workers, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mimeoed bills of programmes, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General administrative details, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General paperwork, mostly notes of Edward Rice, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Series 11: Administration, dates not examined; 2 folders
  - General administrative directives and forms, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous paperwork, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series 12: “The Edward Rice Case”, dates not examined; 1 folder
  - Papers and correspondences of Edward Rice, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Series 13: Federal Art Project, dates not examined; 1 folder
  - Graphic illustration, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series 14: Federal Music Project, 1937-1939; 1 folder
  - Notices and programmes for concerts and operas, 1937-1939; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series 15: Programs in New York Collections, 1936; 1 box
  - Survey of state and local historical records of programs deposited in New York collections, made by the Works Progress Administration, 1936; 1 box (Box 7)